A Finding Aid to the Nancy Spero Papers, 1940s-2009, in the Archives of American Art AAA.spernanc
Archives of American Art
Nancy Spero papers
1940s-2009
AAA.spernanc
Archives of American Art
26.9 Linear feet
The papers of painter, collage artist, and printmaker Nancy Spero measure 26.9 linear feet and are dated 1940s-2009. Biographical materials, correspondence, interviews, writings, subject files, personal business records, printed material, and photographic materials provide an overview of her exhibitions, major projects, and personal life. Also documented is her interest and participation in political movements and social issues including anti-war, women's rights, animal rights, repressive regimes, and the treatment of political prisoners.
Spero, Nancy, 1926-2009
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original material requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Nancy Spero in 1979. The majority of the collection was donated by her sons, Stephen Golub, Philip Golub, and Paul Golub in 2013.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged in 9 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1950-2009 (Boxes 1-2; 1.4 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1946-2009 (Boxes 2-4; 2 linear feet)
Series 3: Interviews, 1973-2007 (Boxes 4-5; 0.8 linear foot)
Series 4: Writings, 1950-2003 (Box 5; 0.8 linear foot)
Series 5: Subject Files, circa 1950-2009 (Boxes 6-18, 29, RD 30; 12.6 linear feet)
Series 6: Personal Business Records, circa 1976-2008 (Boxes 18-19; 1 linear foot)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1949-2009 (Boxes 19-25; 6.1 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographic Material, 1940s-2009 (Boxes 25-26, 29; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 9: Video Recordings, 1970s-1990s (Boxes 26-28; 1 linear foot)
Scope and Contents note
The papers of painter, printmaker, and collage artist Nancy Spero measure 26.9 linear feet and are dated 1940s-2009. Biographical materials, correspondence, interviews,writings, subject files, personal business records, printed material, and photographic materials provide an overview of her exhibitions, major projects, and personal life. Also documented is her interest and participation in political and social movements including anti-war, women's rights, animal rights, and raising awareness about repressive regimes, and the treatment of political prisoners.
Biographical materials include 29 audiovisual recordings about Nancy Spero and her work. Also found are biographical notes, resumes, and her passport. Correspondence concerns exhibitions, projects, travel, general news of family and friends, social events, and fundraising for political and social causes that Spero supported.
Interviews with Spero, conducted for a variety of purposes, include 7 audiovisual recordings, many transcripts, and published versions. Also, there are several joint interviews with Nancy Spero and Leon Golub. Spero's writings consist of notes, artist's statements, and articles. Also included are 7 audiovisual recordings of talks by Spero and her participation in panel discussions.
Subject files document many of Spero's personal and professional projects, relationships, and interests. Especially well documented is A.I.R. Gallery which includes 42 sound cassettes of talks presented in its "Current Issues and Events" series (1982-1984), gallery correspondence, exhibition documentation, and records of the A.I.R. Partnership.
Personal business records include many inventories and lists. Also documented are gifts, loans, sales, prices, reproduction permissions and fees. Printed material consists of a variety of items such as books, clippings, exhibition catalogs and announcements, periodicals, press releases and reproductions. Many items mention Spero and/or include reproductions of her work. Also found with printed material are 22 commercially produced audiovisual recordings about various subjects.
Photographic materials include photographs, digital images, slides, negatives and color transparencies of artwork, exhibition installations, and people. Artwork is mainly by Spero and exhibition installations record some of her solo shows. Images of people include Nancy Spero, Leon Golub, unidentified friends and family members.
Biographical/Historical note
Nancy Spero (1926-2009) was a figurative painter, printmaker, and collage artist in New York City whose multi-media work often incorporated text. She was an ardent feminist and activist whose political and social concerns were expressed in her art.
Born in Cleveland, Nancy Spero lived in Chicago from the time she was a very young child until completing her studies at the School of the Art Institute of Chicago (BFA 1949) where she met her future husband, painter Leon Golub (1922-2004). She studied briefly in Paris and lived in New York City, returning to Chicago after her marriage in 1951. The couple and their two sons lived in Italy from 1956 to 1957. In 1959, after a few years in New York, the family moved to Paris where Spero developed an interest in existentialism and produced a series of black paintings. When Spero and Golub returned to New York in 1964, their family consisted of three sons.
Nancy Spero was strongly affected by the war in Vietnam and the many social changes of the period. She became a social activist and feminist, joined various organizations, and participated in a variety of demonstrations. Work such as the War series began to include political and sexual imagery. Spero was among the founding members of the women's cooperative A.I.R. Gallery established in 1972. In 1974 she decided to make women in mythology, history, art, and literature the exclusive subject of her work. Included in this vein are major series and installations, among them Torture of Women, Notes in Time on Women, The First Language, and her 66th Street/Lincoln Center subway station mosaic mural Artemis, Acrobats, Divas and Dancers.
Spero exhibited in the 1950 Salon des Independents and her first solo exhibition (in tandem with Leon Golub) was held at Indiana University in 1958. Thereafter, she showed sporadically until nearly 30 years later when her career flourished and she enjoyed international stature. Beginning in 1986, each year brought multiple solo exhibitions at galleries and museums in the United States and internationally. In addition, she continued to participate in group shows such as "Documenta" and the Venice Biennale. Her work is included in the permanent collections of museums throughout the world.
Awards and honors included the Skowhegan Medal for Works on Paper (1995), Hiroshima Art Prize shared with Leon Golub (1996), The Women's Caucus for Art award for Outstanding Achievement in Visual Arts (2003), and The Women's Caucus for Art Distinguished Artist Award for Lifetime Achievement (2005). Spero was awarded honorary Doctorates of Fine Arts by The School of the Art Institute of Chicago (1991) and Williams College (2001), and was elected a member of the American Academy of Arts and Letters (2006).
After several years of declining health, Nancy Spero died from heart failure in New York City, October 18, 2009.
Related Archival Materials note
Also among the holdings of the Archives of American Art an interview of Nancy Spero conducted 2008 Februay 6-July 24, by Judith Olch Richards, and the papers of Spero's husband, Leon Golub.
A.I.R. Gallery, (New York, N.Y.); Golub, Leon, 1922-2004; Art--Political aspects; Collagists--New York (State)--New York; Feminism; Interviews; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Peace movements; Photographs; Printmakers--New York (State)--New York; Slides; Sound recordings; Transcripts; Video recordings; Women artists--New York (State)--New York
- Biographical Material, 1950-2009; Series 1; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes 1 motion picture film and 28 audiovisual recordings (1 U-matic, 21 VHS, 5 DVD, and 1 Hi8) about Nancy Spero and her work. One passport for the period 1996-2006 is a photocopy.
  - About Spero and her Work, circa 1986-2006; Includes 1 film reel: 8mm; 1 videocassette (U-matic); 1 videocassette (Hi8); 21 videocassettes (VHS); 5 video discs (DVD) (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
  - Biographical Notes, circa 1998-circa 2004; undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Curricula Vitae, circa 1979-circa 2007 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - Obituary, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Membership Card, Passports, and International Certificates of Vaccination, 1950-1959; 1980-2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Phone Numbers, circa 2000s (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1946-2009; Series 2; 2 Linear feet Boxes 2-4
  Professional correspondence is with museums, art dealers, artists' organizations, groups representing many political and social issues of interest to Spero, and others. Topics include exhibitions, projects, publications, travel, and fundraising. Personal correspondence with family and friends includes general news, invitations to a variety of social events, greeting cards, and drawings by grandchildren.
  Arrangement note
  Correspondence is arranged by year. The majority of Spero's professional correspondence is scattered among subject files (Series 5) and a few letters from authors are attached to manuscripts about Spero and her work (Series 4).
  - Correspondence, 1946-1995; undated (Box 2, Folder 8-21)
  - Correspondence, 1996-2006 (Box 3, Folder 1-20)
  - Correspondence, 2007-2009 (Box 4, Folder 1-6)
- Interviews, 1973-2007; Series 3; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 4-5
  Interviews were conducted by curators, art historians, students, and writers for exhibition research, articles, student papers, and other purposes. Included are 7 videocassettes (VHS), transcripts, and published versions. Most of the transcripts are edited versions; in some cases, there are multiple versions. Many were published, sometimes years after the interview. Also, there are several joint interviews with Nancy Spero and Leon Golub.
  Transcripts are arranged by interview date and published versions by date of publication. Additional interviews are found among the subject files (Series 5) and with printed material (Series 7).
  - Nancy Spero Interviews (Transcripts), undated; 1975-2007 (Box 4, Folder 7-14)
  - Nancy Spero Interviews, Published Versions (Transcripts), 1973-2004 (Box 4, Folder 15-18)
  - Nancy Spero Interviews, 1990s-1996; 6 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
  - Nancy Spero and Leon Golub Interviews (Transcripts), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Nancy Spero and Leon Golub Interviews, Published Versions (Transcripts), 1977-2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Nancy Spero and Leon Golub Interview, 1992; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Writings, 1950-2003; Series 4; 0.8 Linear feet Box 5
  Writings by Spero include a variety of notes and artist's statements. Talks and panel discussions are documented by notes, texts, and 5 videocassettes (VHS). There are published versions of articles about the Whitney Museum's treatment of women artists, pursuing her career while raising a family, and other topics. In addition, there are published versions of forewords to a small book about Cesarini Sforza and the catalog of an exhibition for which she was the sole juror. Writings by other authors are about Spero and miscellaneous subjects.
  Spero's writings are arranged by format. Those by others are alphabetized by author. Additional writings by Spero and others are found among the subject files (Series 5).
  - By Spero (Box 5)
    - Articles, Published Versions, 1971-1994 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, Published Versions, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Notes, circa 1967; undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Poem, "The Jew", 1950 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Statements, undated; 1966-2003 (Box 5, Folder 9-13)
    - Statements, Published Versions, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Talks and Panel Discussions, 1989-1992; undated; Includes 5 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 5, Folder 15-17)
  - About Spero, A-Z by Author, 1970s-2003 (Box 5, Folder 18-25)
  - Miscellaneous Topics, A-Z by Author, circa 1970s-circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Subject Files, circa 1950-2009; Series 5; 12.6 Linear feet Boxes 6-18, 29, RD 30
  Subject files are comprised of correspondence, writings, printed items, photographs, and audiovisual materials in varying combinations. Audiovisual recordings consist of 42 sound cassettes, 1 sound disc (CD), 5 video discs (DVD), 30 videocassettes (VHS), and 4 computer discs (3.5"). The files document Spero's professional and personal projects, activities, relationships, and interests. Among the most extensively documented subjects are: A.I.R. Gallery, animals, Baltic Center for Contemporary Art exhibition, Barbara Gross Galerie, benefits, Centro Galego de Arte Contemporanea exhibition, Christine König Galerie, Codex Artaud, Hiroshima City Museum of Contemporary Art, Josh Baer Gallery, Kunsthalle zu Kiel, Metropolitan Transit Authority Project for 66th Street/Lincoln Center Subway Station ( Artemis, Acrobats, Divas and Dancers), Museu d'Art Contemporani de Barcelona traveling exhibition, Museum of Fine Arts Boston banners, Venice Biennale 52 (2007), and women. Other files of note are: Jon Bird, Clayton Eshelman, Deborah Frizzell, Paul Golub, Philip Golub, Stephen Golub, Ana Mendieta, Rick [Ulrich] and Harriet Meyer, Museum of Modern Art Notes in Time gift of Ulrich Meyer, Hans-Ulrich Obrist, and Rip Off File.
  This series is alphabetized by folder title. Filing is inconsistent; for example, subject files concerning exhibitions and loans may be filed by exhibition title, museum or gallery, and sometimes by city or country. Correspondence (Series 2) may include individuals, institutions, exhibitions and events represented by subject files.
  - Afghanistan, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "After Auschwitz: Responses to the Holocaust in Contemporary Art" (1995-1996), Northern Center for Contemporary Art, Sutherland, England, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Agnes B., 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - A.I.R. "Current Issues and Events" Series, List of Sound Cassettes, circa 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - A.I.R. "Current Issues and Events" Series, Recordings, 1982 October 3-December 18, 1982 October 3-1982 December 18; 14 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - A.I.R. "Current Issues and Events" Series, Recordings, 1983 October 23-1983 December 4; 16 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - A.I.R. "Current Issues and Events" Series, Recordings, 1984 February 25-1984 May 20; 12 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - A.I.R. Gallery, "A.I.R. Gallery Founding Members," Women's History Month Talk by Pat Mainardi at The CUNY Graduate Center (2007 March 5), circa 2007; 1 Sound discs (CD) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - A.I.R. Gallery Correspondence, 1976-2008 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - A.I.R. Gallery Exhibitions, 1972-2000 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - A.I.R. Partnership, 1980-1994 (Box 6, Folder 11-16)
  - Alloway, Lawrence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Altmann, Susanne, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - American Academy in Rome, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - The American Academy of Arts and Letters, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Amsterdam, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Andrea Rosen Gallery, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "Angel, Angel" (1997 June 6-September 7), Kunsthalle Wein, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Animals, undated (Box 6, Folder 24-26)
  - Animals, 1970s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Anthony Reynolds Gallery, 1990-2008 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Apexart, "Neo-Sincerity: The Difference between the Comic and the Cosmic is a Single Letter" (2006 February 22-April 8), Amei Wallach, Curator (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Archive for Research in Archetypal Symbolism, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Arkesteijn, Roel -- Book, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Art 21 -- Art in the Twenty-first Century" PBS Series, 2005-2007; Includes 1 video disc (DVD) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Art 2000 -- Clinton, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Art Gallery of Ontario, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - A.R.T. Resources, "Nancy Spero and Dana Shottenkirk, Paganism and Platonism" (2001 Febuary 3-24) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Art to Go, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Artimo, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Artists Call Against U.S. Intervention in Central America, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Artists Space, 1989-2001; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - The Atlanta College of Art and Design, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The ATM Gallery/Gallery B, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - "Atomica: Making the Invisible Visible" (2005 June 19-August 31), Esso Gallery (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Awards, 1998-2003 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Baltic Centre for Contemporary Art, Gateshead, England, 2002-2004; Includes 1 videodisc (DVD) (Box 7, Folder 22-24)
  - Barbara Gross Galerie, undated; 1988-2009 (Box 7, Folder 25-33)
  - Barbara Gross Galerie, Spero Inventories, 1987-1994 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Benefits, 1991-2008 (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
  - Bennington College, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Berlin/Bonn/Munich, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Bird, Jon, 1986-2008 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - The Black and the Red, III, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Boabab Frames, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "Boeckl-Preis fur Nancy Spero" (2009), Museum der Moderne, Salzburg (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Boston Lecture, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Bourgeois, Louise, undated; 1994-2008 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Brooks, Rosetta, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Brandeis Cultural Center, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Bucknell University Art Gallery, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Burnett-Miller Gallery, undated; 1986-1997 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Burning In Hell" (1991 September 27-December 14), Nancy Spero, Curator, 1991-1995 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - "Cairo Biennial" (1998), 1997-2000 (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
  - Card Designs, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Centre Georges Pompidou, "Feminine-Masculine: The Sex of Art" (1995 October 24-1996 February 12), 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    Includes 1 videocassette: (VHS)
  - Centro Andaluz de Arte Contemporaneo, "Disidanzas Nancy Spero" (2009 January 29-March 22 (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
  - Centro Galego de Arte Contemporanea, Nancy Spero: Weighing the Heart against a Feather of Truth" (2004 September 24-2005 January 6), 2002-2004; Includes 1 video disc (DVD) (Box 8, Folder 25-27)
  - Chicago, Harold Washington Library Project, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - China -- "Re-Configuration: Works on Paper at the Yanhuang Museum" (2001 April 21-May 12) (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Christine König Galerie, undated; 1992-2009 (Box 8, Folder 30-33)
  - City Arts, 1997-2001 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - City Gallery of Contemporary Art, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - City of Barcelona Prize (awarded 2008), 2009 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Clemente, Chiara, 2006-2008 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Codex Artaud, undated; 1972-2001; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Codex Artaud, Quotations Translated by Philip Golub, circa 1970s (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Oversized material housed in RD 30
  - College Art Association, 2003-2007 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - College of St. Rose, undated; 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Costantini, Giovanna, 2005-2007 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Crown Gallery, 1997-2003 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - De Appel Arts Centre, 2008-2009 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Declero, Joost (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Denmark, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Derry, Northern Ireland, 1987-1990; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Dickinson College, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Documenta X" (1997 June 21-September 28), 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - "Documenta 50 Years" (2005 September 1-November 30) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Dogs, undated; 1970s (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - The Drawing Center, "Persistent Vestiges: Drawings from the American-Vietnam War" (2005 November 3-December 23), 2004-2005 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Dresden, Festspielhaus Hellerau Installation (1998), 1996-1999; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
  - Dresden, "Let's Talk about Sex" (2001 December 6-2002 February 10), 2001-2002 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Editions Fawbush, 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Egyptian Images, Brooklyn Museum, 2002; undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - El Salvador, 1981-1999 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Engaged Artists/Public Matters, 1983
  - Eshelman, Clayton, undated; 1967-2006 (Box 9, Folder 25-26)
  - Everson Museum of Art, "Nancy Spero: Work Since 1950" (1987 December 18-1988 January 31), 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Exhibitions, 1994-2003 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - "The Feminine Image" (1996 November 17-1997 January 26), Nassau County Museum of Art, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Feminism, 1970s-2007; undated (Box 9, Folder 30-31)
  - "Feminist Art of the '70s" Exhibition Proposal, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - The Feminist Memoir Project, 1993-1998 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Finland - "Ars 01" (2001 September 30-2002 January 20), Museum of Contemporary Art, Helsinki, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - The First Language, A.I.R. Gallery, Ramapo College, Galerie France Morin, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Frac, 2001-2007 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Franco Soffiantino Arte Contemporanea, 2006-2009 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Frankfurt, "Prospect 89", 1988 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Frizzell, Deborah, 1998-2009; undated; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 6-8)
  - Frizzell, Deborah, Tibetan Mapping Project, Image Suggestions, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Galeria Filomena Soares, "Nancy Spero" (2003 April 10-May 17) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Galerie Darthea Speyer, 1994-2000 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Galerie de France, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Galerie France Morin, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Galerie Lelong, 2002-2009 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Galerie Monteney, Paris, 1990-2001; undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Glasgow Art Gallery and Museum, 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "The Glass Mountain", circa 2003 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Glen Ridge High School, circa 1997 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Globe, 1999; undated (Box 10, Folder 19, Folder 20-21)
  - Golub, Paul, undated; 1962-1969; circa 1962-2008; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
  - Golub, Philip, 1955-1959; 2005-2007 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Golub, Stephen, circa 1950s; 1970s-2008; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 23-25)
  - Golub, Stephen, Williams College Museum of Art, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "Goya to Bejing" (1990), Bonner Kunstverein (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Grant Applications, 1976-circa 1985 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Guild Hall, "Personal and Political: The Women's Art Movement, 1969-1975" (2002 August 10-October 20) (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Haggadah, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Harbor School, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Harvard University Art Museums, 1995-2000 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Hebrew Union College -- Jewish Institute of Religion, 1990-1997 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Heresies, 1977-1986; undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Herstory of Women Artists in Revolution, circa 1971 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Hiroshima City Museum of Contemporary Art, undated; 1996-2005; Includes 2 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 36-38)
  - Hirschman, Jack, undated; circa 1967-1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Hirshfield, Pearl, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - History -- Women, etc., 1979-1980s; undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Hobart and William Smith Colleges, 1986-2002 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Holzer, Jenny, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Homeless Fashion, Hans-Ulrich Obrist and Richard Martin, undated; 1990-2005 (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
  - Honolulu Academy of Arts, 1990-1993 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hours of the Night, 2000; Includes 2 floppy disks (3.5") (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - ICA, London -- "Nancy Spero, Works 1954-1986" (1987 March 11-April 20), Includes 1 videocassette: (VHS) (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
  - Ideas, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - IKON Gallery, 1997-1999 (Box 11, Folder 13-14)
  - Illinois State University, Normal, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 15)